歌洛莉亚 确保不能让杰发现
Okay, Gloria, just make sure Jay doesn't find out.
天呐
Oh. Boy.
我刚意识到
I just heard that.
你该误会我和歌洛莉亚有情况了吧
You probably think there's something between me and Gloria.
别紧张
Relax.
我昏迷的时候都没有现在这么放松
I couldn't be more relaxed if I was in a coma.
杰的烤架刚刚送到
Jay's grill was delivered.
她把烤架藏起来
She's keeping it under wraps
等我到的时候再给他看
so I can be there when he sees it!
天呐
Oh, my God!
我刚被加州理工录取了
I just got accepted into Caltech.
真的吗
You did?!
太棒了
That is incredible!
我们家要出大科学家了
We're gonna have a famous scientist in the family!
学一门实在的手艺也没什么可耻的
Uh, not that there's any shame in learning a trade.
空调总是会坏掉的
Air conditioners are always gonna break.
我查过了 要上的课太多了
Eh, I looked into it. It's a lot of classes.
亲爱的 真是不可思议
Honey, that is unbelievable.
没什么不可思议的
It's hardly unbelievable.
超厉害小孩 上超厉害学校
Super-smart kid, super-smart school.
我从不怀疑你
I never doubted you.
一定感觉很棒
That must feel great.
对啊 棒极了
Yep. Pretty great.
这是怎么回事
What was that?
我觉得是我的错
I think that was my fault.
我也觉得 为什么
Me too. Why?
我总是这样
I do this all the time.
她这么了不起 而我却习以为常了
She does these amazing things, and I'm so used to it,
被加州理工录取我都没太当回事
I don't even make a big deal over Caltech.
我这么兴奋 这还不算吗
I got excited. Doesn't that count?
亲爱的 什么事都会让你兴奋
Well, honey, you get excited over everything.
你天生就是个啦啦队长
You're a born cheerleader.
我今天要给艾丽克斯好好宣传庆祝一下
I just need to make a really big fuss over Alex today.
就这样
That's all.
我知道 你不爽
I know -- you're upset
因为我说你天生是个
because I said that you were a born --
没有什么天生的啦啦队长
There's no such thing as a born cheerleader.
刻苦训练 作出大量牺牲才能当上的
It takes hard work and sacrifice.
你知道没有充分训练
You know what a human pyramid
就跳人体金字塔会怎么样吗
is without hours of training?
10条人命就没了
10 obituaries.
我想我爸今年会很享受退掉礼物的过程
I think my dad is really gonna enjoy returning his gift this year.
米奇尔 我有个非常悲伤的消息
Mitchell, I have some really sad news.
是啊 看你心都碎了
Yes, you seem very broken up.
是这样 我有个叔叔 叫赛勒斯
Apparently, I had an uncle, uh, Cyrus,
去世了 竟给我留了一笔
who died and out of the blue
相当可观的遗产
left me a pretty handsome sum.
我猜他没什么近亲吧
I-I guess he didn't have a lot of other kin.
只有这次我不介意你说这个词
Okay, this is the one time I don't mind you saying "Kin."
你说"可观的"[英俊的]
Now, when you say "handsome,"
是指莉莉学校里那个拼车的父亲
are we talking carpool dad at Lily's school
还是更像克鲁尼或者皮特那样的
or are we in a more Clooney/Pitt area?
我觉得是哈利·哈姆林那样的
I would say more Harry Hamlin.
那还真是不错
That's not bad at --
相当不错啊
That's not bad at all.
真是不可思议 因为我刚刚看到
You know, and this is crazy, because, um, I just saw
楼上的房子开始出售了
that the upstairs unit went back on the market,
这笔哈利·哈姆林正好够首付
and Harry Hamlin would almost equal a down payment, and --
我 抱歉 抱歉
I'm -- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
瞧我 随意决定如何花你的钱
Look at me, spending your money.
不 米奇尔 这不是我的钱
No, Mitchell, it's not my money.
是我们的钱
It's our money.
这是个信号吗 小卡
I-is this a sign, Cam?
我们一直都在说这事
I mean, we talk about it all the time.
我们应该把楼上的公寓买下来
We should buy that upstairs apartment.
为什么不买呢
I don't see a reason why not!
真是太棒了
This is so exciting.
我知道
I know.
我真为你骄傲
I'm really proud of you,
因为曾经有段时间
because there was a time
我根本不可能看到这张支票
when I wouldn't have even seen this check.
是啊
Oh, well, yes.
我以前老是冲动消费
You know, I used to be quite the impulse buyer.
但我再也不是那样的人了
But I don't even recognize that guy anymore.
我喜欢我的新人造貂皮大衣 大爸
I love my new faux mink, daddy.
我又忘了 我是嘉宝姐妹中的哪个来着
I forgot -- which Gabor sister am I?
你是艾娃 漂亮的那个 但是听我说
Y-you're Eva, the classy one, but listen.
我们得留着吊牌 因为要把衣服退回去
We need to keep the tags on it, because it's going back.
那你的也得退
Well, then yours is going back, too.
不行 那太难了
No, that's a hard thing,
因为店员说我穿上像日瓦戈医生
because the saleslady said I look like Dr. Zhivago.
所以这算是你的生日礼物
So, is that a birthday present for you
还是你在经历严重迟到的中年危机
or an extremely late mid-life crisis?
"严重"这词没必要吧
I don't think "extremely" is necessary.
这是借的 一周的试驾期
It's on loan -- kind of a weekend-long test-drive.
我走进一家店
I walk into a store,
他们害我把我的背包留给了他们
they make me leave my backpack behind the counter.
这是汽车销售员的惯用策略
It's an old car salesman's trick.
他们希望我爱上这辆车 然后买下
They're hoping I fall in love with it and never give it back.
但我找不到买这辆车的理由
But I can't justify buying it
就像你没有理由买那顶帽子
any more than you can justify that hat.
现在喝龙舌兰酒有点早吧
Little early for tequila, isn't it?
给卢克的
It's for Luke.
这理由有更合适吗
Not sure that's better.
他上次来的时候
The last time he was here,
他看这瓶酒的样子 跟你看到我
he was eyeing this bottle the same way you look at me
穿吊带裙时的样子一模一样
when I wear that strappy sundress.
我真的很喜欢那条裙子
I do like that dress.
我要抓他个现行
I am going to catch him red-handed.
给他点教训
I am going to teach him a lesson.
但我要先在这酒瓶里装上白水
But first I'm going to refill this with water
免得他趁我没注意真的喝了
in case he gets past me.
他们还要再过会儿才到
You know, we have a little time before the family comes.
要不你穿上那条裙子
Why don't you throw that dress on and --
该死
Aw, damn it.
安迪 你能去开门吗
Andy, can you get that?
安迪
Andy?
抱歉
Sorry.
你们开始调情的时候我就没在听了
I tuned out when you started flirting
好给你们一点私人空间
to give you some privacy.
海莉上次到医院看我以后
I was seeing Haley for the first time
我还没有再见过她
since she came to visit me in the hospital.
她说了一些很深情的话
She said some pretty heavy stuff.
如果我就是你的大象
If I'm your elephant,
你是有机会追到我的
you have a shot.
我想说的就是这个 傻瓜
That's what I'm trying to say, dummy.
她不知道我听到了
She didn't know I heard.
我花了一个星期想忘掉这句话
I tried for a couple weeks to forget about it
继续跟贝丝在一起
and just go on with Beth,
但我没法不想着海莉
but I couldn't stop thinking about Haley.
所以我决定今天跟她摊牌
So... today's the day I'm finally gonna have the big talk.
后院有一冰柜的饮料 大家随意
There's a cooler of drinks out back! Help yourselves!
海莉呢 她会来吗
Where's Haley? Is she coming?
海莉上一次跟我说她的计划时 她说
The last time Haley informed me of her plans, she said,
"我要去卡布了 不带你哦"
"Ha ha. I'm going to Cabo, and you're not."
她最棒了
She's the best.
准备面对你最棒的礼物吧
Get ready to see the best gift ever.
生日快乐
Happy birthday!
烧烤炉 我有一个烧烤炉了
It's a grill. I got a grill.
你以前也有一个老婆
You had a wife, too.
但不代表你不能换一个
Didn't mean you couldn't trade up.
我送你的是巨焰牌烤炉
I give you the Flame XL.
我的客户是那家公司的老板
My client owns the company.
他给了我一个超值大礼包
He gave me a crazy-good deal.
送了25000热单位的丙烷燃料
25,000 wood propane BTUs.
那...很多 是吧
That's... plenty, right?
不 这是电转烤肉架
No. Electric rotisserie!
如果上帝想吃汉堡
If god wants a hamburger,
她肯定是用这个来烤肉
this is what she cooks it on.
这么多没用的小玩意儿
But it's got all those doodads.
我不知道要拿来干什么
I don't know what to do with those doodads.
你假装不兴奋
You're doing a great job
装得很好
of hiding your excitement about this gift.
你看 很简单的
Look. It's simplicity itself.
打开气阀 点火
You just turn on the gas, hit the electric starter.
点火
Hit the electric starter.
菲尔 你可能要放一下手
Phil, you might want to lay off --
我没事
I'm fine.
一如既往的健康
Healthy as ever.
我很清楚 我刚刚看到了你的X光片
I'd know if you weren't, 'cause I just saw your skeleton.
好了 乔
Okay, Joe.
该在你的新床上睡个午觉了
Time for a nap in your new bed!
你在找什么吗
Looking for something?
对 找你
Uh, yeah -- you.
我想说你的派对办得太棒了
I just wanted to say what a nice party you put together.
秘密就是了解宾客们的喜好
The secret is to know what your guests want,
而我知道你想要什么
and I know what you want.
卢克 给你上一课
Hey, Luke, quick lesson.
这是杯垫 能避免杯子留水印
This is a coaster. It prevents rings.
真是多谢你的乐倍汽水
Thanks to you and your Dr pepper,
我楼上的柚木桌现在看起来像奥运旗
my teak end table upstairs looks like the olympic flag.
用脑子 卢克
Think, Luke.
是的 用脑子 卢克
Yes. Think, Luke.
你拿到了吗
Did you get it?
是的
Yep.
美妙的墨西哥宝藏
Sweet Mexican treasure.
我是在佛罗里达出生的 不过谢谢
I was born in Florida, but thank you.
你真的决定要买了吗
So, you really think you're gonna buy it?
确实有必要
I mean, it makes sense.
我们现在住得有点挤
We're kind of cramped where we are.
她来了 我们的天才少女
There she is -- our little genius.
她刚被加州理工录取了
She just got accepted to Caltech.
太棒了
Oh, that's amazing!
没什么了不起的
It's not that big of a deal.
很了不起
It's a huge deal!
这学校出的诺贝尔奖得主
That school pumps out Nobel prize winners
比我们学校被搞大肚子的女生一样多
the way my school pumped out stomachs.
妈 够了
Enough, mom!
你这是要干嘛
what was that about?
知道她被加州理工录取的时候
I didn't make a big enough fuss
我们表现得不够激动
about her getting into Caltech,
现在我该付出代价了
and now she's making me pay.
如果她的不爽只有这么点的话
Well, if that's her giving you a hard time,
那你应该很容易就混过去了
I think you got off pretty easy.
你说得没错
Well, that's true.
她基本没有叛逆期
That one never really went through a rebellious phase.
还记得我们以前有多疯狂吗
Remember how wild we were?
我们有吗
Were we ever!
Were we ever?
没有 没有
Not really, no.
你顶了一暑假的红色爆炸头
You had your summer of the red afro,
而我曾跟世上最白的波多黎各人约会
and I dated the whitest Puerto Rican on earth.
韦恩
Oh, Wayne.
但那不代表我们没有离开家
Hey, but it's not like we didn't separate
开始拼搏自己的人生
and strike out on our own.
-对吗 -说得没错
- Am I right? - Yeah! That's right.
老爸给我买的房子
Dad bought me my house.
我们的也是
Ours, too.
他借给我们首付的钱
He loaned us the money for the down payment.
我们一直没还
We never paid him back.
我一直感觉很惭愧
I've always felt so guilty.
他也帮我们出了首付
You know, he gave us our down payment, too.
你确定不是送的吗
Are you sure that wasn't a gift?
我从来没说过要还他 我不知道
Well, I never offered to pay him back. I don't know.
他还刚给我发了一笔奖金
And then he just gave me this bonus at work.
他该是怎么看我的啊
What he must think of me.
已经过去那么久了
It's so long ago now.
不管怎样
Well, still.
我觉得应该把钱还给他
I feel like I should offer to pay him back.
什么 不不不 不要 克莱尔
What -- no. N-no. No, no, no, no, no, no, Claire.
那样我也得还他钱了
Because then I'm gonna have to pay him back,
那我就只能待在他上次给我买的
and I'll be stuck in the same shoe box
小鸽子笼里
he bought me last time.
米奇尔 他不会收的
Mitchell, he's not going to accept it.
这只是一个姿态
It's just a gesture.
我们这么做只是想显得更独立
We do it so we feel more independent.
听我的
Just do it.
把钱还给他
Do it!
还什么
Do what?
没什么 你忙着呢
Oh, nothing. You're busy.
一点也不忙
Not really.
菲尔还在鼓捣新的烧烤机
Phil's tinkering with the new grill,
你最好开始准备他葬礼上用的旧照片了
so you better collect some old photographs for the memorial.
所以要还什么
Do what?
你可能不记得了
Well, you probably don't remember this.
但是之前
But, a while back,
你帮我们垫了房子的首付
you gave us some money for a down payment.
非常大方的举动 是的
Very generously, I might add. Yes.
-这不只是因为你今天生日 -没错
- And not just cause it's your birthday... - That's right.
我们觉得至少应该提出
...but we wanted to at least make the offer
把钱还给你
to pay...you...back.
米奇尔 你在干什么 这我不能兑现
Mitchell, what are you doing? I can't cash this.
老爸 我
Now, dad, I--
你得签字啊
You got to sign it first.
那样的话
Okay, in that case,
我得把笔拿回来
I'm gonna need to get the pen back from--
克莱尔
Claire!
我这里就有
Got one right here.
那好
Okay.
你好啊
Hey, you.
我没想着能在这里见到你
I didn't expect to see you here today.
你感觉怎么样了
How you feeling?
好多了 原来人没有阑尾也能活
Better. Turns out you don't even need an appendix.
我完全不想念我的阑尾
I don't even miss it anymore.
它就像已消失的电路城一样
It's like Circuit City.
我一直有话想跟你说
Anyway, I've been wanting to talk to you about something.
这房子太棒了
This house is fantastic.
我应该做衣柜生意的
I should have gone into the closet business.
我说得没错吧
Right?
我在领他参观呢 安迪 这是威尔
I'm giving him a tour. Andy, this is Will.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
抱歉 我要接这个电话
I'm sorry. I have to take this.
是医院的事
It's the hospital.
他是医生
He's a doctor.
我在去医院看你的那天遇见他的
I met him the same day I came to visit you in the hospital.
是不是很有趣
Isn't that funny?
非常有趣
Super-funny.
对了 你想跟我说什么
So, wait. What did you want to talk to me about?
就是这个小魔王
Just that this little heck-raiser
该午睡了 但他一直不肯上床
needs to take a nap, but he's been fighting it.
我有办法 卢克以前也这样
Oh, I've got an idea. Luke had the same problem.
我累了
I'm tired.
得上床睡觉觉
Let's go to bed.
我们一起吗
Both of us?
我们两个都要上来吗
Together? Me too?
是啊 因为我们困了 该睡午觉了
Yes, because we are sleepy and it's nap time!
等着吧 他会爬上床加入我们的
Now wait. He'll climb in bed with us.
给他点时间
Just give him a minute.
好吧
Okay.
既然我们都躺在床上
Since we're just lying here...
你还记得当你
do you remember when you --
抱歉
Sorry about that.
天呐
Oh! Gosh!
Oh, Gosh.
你才出去两分钟
You're gone for two minutes,
回来就发现我们躺在一起
you come back and find us in the big-boy bed.
我知道你是怎么想的
I can only imagine what you're thinking.
你们是在哄小孩子睡觉吧
That you're trying to get this little kid to take a nap?
看他多聪明
How smart is he?
说几句医学用语
Say something medical.
20cc 马上
20cc, stat.
我完全听不懂 但是听起来好刺激
I don't understand a word, but it gets me going.
这算什么购物政策啊
I mean, what kind of store policy is that?
就因为我在家里穿了一次
I-I can't return a coat
就不能退了吗
that I put on one time at home?
你是刚洗完澡时穿的
Getting out of the shower.
你把这事说出来一点帮助都没有
Yeah, you didn't help by pointing that out.
你要怎么跟二爸说
What are you gonna tell daddy?
看来我只能告诉他 我犯了个错
Well, I guess I'm just gonna tell him I made a mistake.
我以前就说过
You know, like I say, sweetie,
诚实永远是最好的办法
honesty is always the best policy.
除非
Unless...
跟着我的思路[留在这陪我]
and stay with me here...
不然我还能去哪里
Where would I go?
我跟你二爸说 让他先别买那套公寓
I convince your daddy to wait on the apartment upstairs
给我留出时间卖掉你的大衣
until I have enough time to sell your coat,
有必要的话 把我的也卖了
and, if need be, even sell mine.
先卖我的大衣 真是谢你了啊
Thanks for selling mine first, Dr. Chicago.
如果我没读错的话
If I'm reading this properly,
我要放一片青柠在你嘴里
I'm supposed to put a lime in your mouth,
在肚皮上撒一点盐
salt on your stomach,
然后从肚脐眼里喝
and drink it out of your bellybutton.
你想得美
You wish.
喝一口就爽飞天
That'll get you there.
我的天
Whoa, nelly.
悠着点 这个酒后劲很大
Hey, pace yourself! This stuff is strong.
我自有分寸
I'll know when I've had enough.
我把它点燃了
I got it lit.
在屋子里都感觉到了
I could feel it inside the house.
法医以后需要牙科记录
They're gonna need dental records
才能辨认那些可怜的烤鸡了
to identify those chickens.
等我打开旋转烤叉
You'll be singing a different tune
你就会对它改观了
once I pop on the rotisserie feature.
准备好天旋地转吧
Get ready for these birds and your head to spin.
这转得也太快了吧
That's moving pretty fast.
调一下就好了
Simple adjustment.
好像还加速了
That seems to have... sped it up.
你能把我们的晚餐从泳池里捞出来吗
H-how about you skim dinner out of my pool?
我去取旧的烤炉
I'll get my old grill out.
为什么会有这种设置
Why is this even a setting?!
你跑到哪里去了 懦夫
Hey, where the hell did you go, you coward?
就因为老爸拿了你的钱
Oh, what, just cause dad took your money back,
我就也要还钱给他吗
I'm supposed to give him all mine, too?
没错 因为是你出的蠢主意
Yes, yes. Because it was your stupid idea. Okay?
天呐 我该怎么跟小卡说
Oh, my god. How am I gonna tell Cam
我把他继承的遗产都白白给人了
I gave away his entire inheritance?
我不知道
I don't know.
这屋里是不是有个未来的医生啊
Oh, hey! Is there a future doctor in the house?
是啊 在楼上和海莉亲热呢
Yeah, I think he's upstairs, feeling up Haley.
不 是你啊 艾利克斯·爱因斯坦
No -- you, Alex Einstein.
不管你在做什么 打住吧
Whatever you're doing, please stop.
她还在生气
She's still mad.
我也是
Yeah, so am I.
这不公平
It's not fair, okay?
老爸给了你们一样的钱交首付
Dad gave you the same amount of money for your down payment.
什么 那钱是杰借的
What? Jay loaned us that money?
天呐 你不知道 没错
Oh, my god. You don't know. Yes. Yes.
让你怀疑她还扯了什么慌 对吧
Makes you wonder what else she's lied about, huh?
等等 我欠了杰20年钱
Wait -- I've owed jay money for 20 years,
你都没跟我说
and you never told me?
我觉得你不会想要
I didn't think you'd want to take it.
我总算知道
I finally understand the invisible wall
我和杰之间为什么总是有隔阂了
that's been between jay and me all this time.
这就是为什么我们没在开那个疯狂烤炉的玩笑
This is why we're not laughing about that crazy grill,
在它旁边来张自拍
taking an awesome selfie with it,
发到社交网络上
posting it on Instagram,
互发搞笑邮件
sending hilarious e-mails back and forth!
"还记得那个破烤架吗"
"Remember when the grill went nuts?"
"记得 超搞笑"
"Oh, yeah. That was hilarious."
"你才搞笑呢"
"You're hilarious."
他不就是个医生吗
So what, he's a doctor?
我也能当医生
I could be a doctor.
在医院前台工作时
I still have the white coat
穿的白大褂我还留着呢
from when I worked at the clinique counter.
歌洛莉亚说该给乔洗澡了
Hey. So, Gloria says it's Joe's bath time.
他刚洗过
He just had one.
浴袍是怎么回事 赫夫
What's with the robe, Hef?
我不知道那是谁 我把衬衫脱了
I don't know who that is, but I took off my shirt
免得被这位神溅手弄湿
to protect it from splash Gordon over here.
好可爱
Adorbs.
能递下那盒果汁吗
Can you grab me that juice box?
好
Yeah, sure.
话说回来...
Anyway...
就像我刚刚说的
Like I was saying before,
记得 我住院时
Remember how, when I was in the hospital --
不好了
Oh, no!
会留下印子的
Oh, man, this is gonna stain!
得把它脱下来泡着
I need to take it off and soak it.
你可以穿我的衬衫 就在那里挂着
You could put on my shirt. It's hanging right there.
谢了
Oh, thanks.
有点大 你有皮带吗
It's a little boxy. Do you have a chunky belt?
有
Uh...yeah, I guess.
开玩笑的
I'm kidding.
反正我又不会穿很长时间
It's not like I'm gonna be wearing this for long anyways.
这看起来很不妙啊
Wow. This looks bad.
这下更糟了
And this looks even worse.
先听我解释
But there's a perfectly good explanation.
宝贝 是不是什么东西撒裙子上了
Hey, babe. You spill something on your dress?
没搞错吧 第一反应是这个啊
Really? That was your first guess?
是啊 给安迪递果汁的时候撒的
Yeah, I was giving Andy a juice box.
不是我喝 我可是成年男人
Mm. Not to drink -- because I'm a man.
我去歌洛莉亚衣橱里
Okay, so, I'm gonna go get a dress
找裙子和鞋
and some shoes from Gloria's closet.
你的鞋怎么了
What happened to your shoes?
没怎么
Nothing.
好吧
Okay.
我一直在观察你们两个
I've been watching the two of you,
事情很明显
and it's pretty obvious.
终于来了
Finally.
你总是能逗她笑
You know how to make her laugh.
我给海莉买了个小礼物
Anyway, I got haley a little gift,
我想在贺卡上写点好听的
and I want to write something cute on the card.
我觉得你能帮上忙 因为
I thought you could help me, because --
因为你不擅长写情话
Because you're not good with words.
我是个医生
Well, I'm a doctor.
我不会说自己有什么不擅长的
I can't admit I'm not good at something.
但...拜托你了
But...please?
好吧
Yeah. Fine.
就写你自己的感觉
Just... write how you feel.
比如说
Something like...
亲爱的海莉 我知道眼睛如何转动
"Dear Haley, I know how eyes work,
却不知道它们如何闪耀
But I never knew how they sparkled until I --"
那可能是黄斑变性
That could be macular degeneration.
你只管写就好
Just write.
我们得醒醒酒
We need to sober up.
等我给前女友打个电话先
Right after I call an ex-girlfriend.
我觉得我还爱着她
I think I still love her.
抱歉 我们来晚了
Hey. Sorry we're late.
没关系 别担心
No, that's fine. No worries.
听着 我的二货姐姐
Um, so, listen, my stupid sister --
我不想买那间公寓了
Look, I don't want that apartment anymore.
我也是
Oh, me neither.
是的 就是...
Yeah, it's just that --
我还以为你铁了心想买呢
Well, I thought you had your heart set on it.
本来是 但你说得也很有道理
I did, but then you made such a compelling case.
米奇 我必须得说 我真没想到
Hey, Mitch, I got to tell you, I was really impressed
你会还我钱
with you paying back that loan.
抱歉 你说什么
I'm sorry. What? Excuse me?
抱歉 也该谢谢你
I'm sorry. I should be thanking you, too.
我都忘了帮你们付过首付
I forgot about that down payment I helped you guys with.
好久以前的事了
It was so long ago.
不管怎么说
Anyway, yeah.
很棒的生日惊喜哦
Nice birthday surprise.
你把我的钱给他了 是吧
You gave him my money, didn't you?
你的钱 你不是说是我们的钱吗
Your money? I thought you said it was our money.
怎么会是我们的钱
Why would it be our money?
你都不认识我雷穆斯舅舅
You didn't even know my uncle Remus.
不是赛勒斯吗
Wasn't it Cyrus?
我想我会记得那个抚养我长大的
I think I would know the name of the saint
圣人的名字
that practically raised me.
我忘记给爷爷生日王冠了
I forgot to give grandpa his birthday crown.
等等 这是什么
Wait a minute. What's this?
莉莉怎么有件毛皮大衣
Does Lily have a fur?
糟糕
Oh, boy.
是啊 瞧瞧
Yeah, uh, let's see.
还是施瓦茨曼家的呢
Oh, it's from Schwartzman's, huh?
那不就是你和莉莉每周日
The same store that you and Lily
吃完早午餐喜欢去逛的店吗
just love to browse in every sunday after brunch.
好 告诉你吧 这是给你的惊喜礼物
Well, if you must know, it was a surprise gift for you.
现在我要退回去 因为你是个小偷
Now it's going back, because you're a thief.
-既然这样我要试试 -不行
- Oh, well, then, I want to try it on. - No!
-我要试穿一下 -你会爱上它的
- I want to try it on. - You'll just get attached.
既然是给我的礼物
Well, it's a present for me,
那是不是该符合我的尺码呢
so I should be able to have a fitting of some sort.
当然需要修改一下了
Of course it needs altering.
不可能从架子上拿下来就穿着合适啊
Since when do you wear right off the rack?
我只是不太习惯用那个维苏威火山
I'm just not comfortable with Vesuvius over there.
我希望你能要回你的钱
I hope you can get your money back.
"要回钱" 就是这个
"Money back" -- there it is.
我们之间的关系
There's a shadow that's been cast
笼罩着一层阴影 经久不散
over this relationship for quite a while now.
你是在说那次你梦游
Is this about that time you were sleepwalking
走进我的帐篷 亲了我的脖子吗
and came in my tent and kissed my neck?
那是梦游求爱症
Somnamorousness --
一种没人愿意谈论的病症
the condition no one wants to talk about.
你说对了
You're right about that.
这其实更让人难堪
This is actually much more embarrassing.
我刚得知你借钱给我们付房子的首付
I just found out you lent us money for our down payment.
所以...
So...
给你
Here.
全额还给你
Paid back in full.
菲尔 这是因为米奇尔...
Phil, is this because Mitchell --
不 这是为了我 为了我们
No. This is for me -- for us.
而且这感谢也许有点迟了
And though it may be long overdue,
不过还是谢谢你
thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
可能看起来有点尴尬 不过...
Probably seems awkward, but...
真的发生了
It's happening.
你能帮我系上围裙吗
...could you throw that apron on me?
你不是又睡着了吧
You're not sleeping again?
也许我们该再喝一壶咖啡
Maybe we should have another pot of coffee.
那词可真怪 咖啡 咖啡 咖啡
That's a weird word, huh? Coffee. Coffee. Coffee.
真外行
Amateur.
医生 我需要你的帮助
Doctor! I need your help.
我在喝这瓶龙舌兰酒
I've been drinking this tequila,
可我找不到蠕虫了
and I cannot find the worm.
我想可能是被我吞了
I think I just swallow it.
那很严重
That's very serious.
蠕虫在几小时内就能吞食你的内脏
That worm could eat your insides in a matter of hours.
一定有什么办法可以抢救吧
Well, there must be something she can do.
喝腌黄瓜汁
Drink pickle juice.
蠕虫在腌黄瓜汁里无法存活
The worm cannot survive in pickle juice.
-这些够了吗 -刚好
- Is this enough? - Just.
谢谢你 医生 我已经感觉好多了
Thank you, doctor. I'm feeling better already.
你很幸运
You got lucky.
另一个治疗办法是泡在冰水浴缸里
The only other treatment is to freeze the worm to death
使体温降低从而将蠕虫冻死
by lowering the body temperature with an ice bath.
我觉得它在我体内蠕动
I feel it inside of me.
不 我觉得在我身体里
No. I think it's inside of me.
我就知道应该把龙舌兰倒进你肚脐里的
I knew we should've poured the tequila in your bellybutton.
这些规矩是有存在的道理的
That's why they have these systems in place.
我听见一部昂贵的轿车开走了
I heard an expensive car pull out.
我以为你在里面呢
I figured you were in it.
是啊 威尔回医院去了
Oh, yeah, that was Will going to the hospital.
我只是来拿我的裙子
I just came to get my dress.
他给我一张卡片 不过字迹太潦草了
Um, he gave me this card, but he writes like a doctor.
你能给我读一下吗
Can you read it for me?
不 那是你们的隐私
No. That sounds way too personal.
拜托 我都去医院看你了
Ohh, come on! I visited you in the hospital.
读吧
Just do it!
不了
Nah, I'm okay.
你看看能不能认出来嘛 我看不懂
Can you just see if you can read it? I can't.
还是算了
I'd rather not.
你识字吗
Can you even read?
-试一下好吗 -好吧 我试试
- Can you please try? - I'll try. Yeah, no, I'll try.
-谢谢你 -不客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
亲爱的海莉 我知道眼睛如何转动
"Dear Haley, I know how eyes work,
但直到遇见你 我才知道
but I never knew how they sparkled
它们有多么闪耀
until I met you.
我知道心脏如何跳动
I know how hearts work,
但直到遇见你 我才知道
but I never knew they could sing
它会歌唱
until I met you.
爱你的威尔
Love, Will."
该死
Oh, crap.
是吗 我觉得写得挺甜蜜的
Really? I thought it was kind of sweet.
以医生的口吻来写他对你的感觉
The doctor part, then it circled around back to you.
他为什么要这么喜欢我呢
Why does he have to be so into me, you know?
我们两周前才认识
We met like two weeks ago.
心形金项链 开什么玩笑
A gold heart! Really?
我只是 我想我更喜欢追求的过程
I just -- I guess I'm just more into the chase right now.
你知道的 那种乐趣
You know, like, the fun.
我还不想开始认真的恋爱关系
I'm just not looking for anything serious.
你知道想要什么 这很好
Well, it's good you know what you want --
免得最后大家都受伤害
Before anyone got hurt.
是啊
Yeah.
谢谢
Thanks.
我当然有收据了
Of course I have the receipt.
要是没有怎么办
Ow!...Kay, what if I didn't?
她来了
Oh, there she is!
各位 让我们举起酒杯
Okay, everybody, I want to make a toast!
又找借口喝酒
Oh, any excuse.
敬我才华横溢的女儿...
To my brilliant daughter...
不是你
So, not you.
努力了12年终于考进加州理工大学
...who worked for 12 years to get into Caltech,
最有威望的学院...
the most prestigious college --
妈妈 真的没什么大不了的
Mom, it's really not a big deal.
亲爱的 等等等等 你自己说过的
Oh, honey, wait, wait, wait -- you said yourself
那是全国最好的科学家学校
it's the best scientist school in the country.
我绝对没有用那些字眼
Well, I most definitely did not use those words.
恭喜你 艾丽克斯
Congratulations, Alex.
我们相信你会有很大的成就
We expect great things from you --
不像这个家里的某些其他孩子
unlike some of the other children in this family.
我钓到了一个医生
Well, I snagged a doctor,
所以她一定是在说你
so she must be talking about you.
我非常为你自豪
I'm very proud of you.
行了 我还没做决定呢
Okay, well, I haven't even decided.
我还是可能去上我的保底学校
I still might go to my safety school.
这下可好
Great. Now this.
要是她决定上另外那所大学
If she goes to the other place,
学费会更高
it's even more expensive.
不会的 拜托
It's not gonna happen. Please.
她只是在惩罚我
She's just trying to punish me.
而且别担心钱的事 有我的奖金呢
And don't worry about the money. I got my bonus.
是啊
Yeah.
慢着 怎么了 你做了什么
Wait. What? What did you do?
你还钱给我爸了吗 拜托你说是的
Did you pay back my dad? Please, please, please.
-不是吧 -是的 我还了
- No, no, no. - Yes, I did.
但并没有改变什么
Not that it changed anything.
好了 别生菲尔的气
Okay, don't be mad at Phil.
他不是这里的恶人 他才是
He's not the bad guy here. He is.
瞧瞧他 坐在那里
Look at him, sitting over there
好像他是全世界的国王似的
like he's the king of the world.
什么样的父亲会收儿女的钱啊
What father takes money from his own children?
他又不需要 他住在这个宫殿里
Not like he needs it. He lives in this palace.
而我们全家人
Meanwhile, our whole family's
共用一间跟他家衣橱一样大的卫生间
sharing a bathroom the size of his closet.
我知道 我用脚量过的
I know. I've paced it out.
好吧 那我呢
Okay, what about me?
我眼里还含着泪呢
My tears have barely dried,
他就偷走了我继承的遗产
he stole my inheritance,
而我却成买了两件毛皮大衣的罪人
and I'm left holding the bag for two fur coats.
两件
T-two?!
那件大衣我可以穿三季
I can get three seasons of use out of it.
这可能会把你们逗笑
Hey, this might give you a chuckle.
你们还给我的那些钱
That money you all paid me back --
刚好够我买下那辆雷鸟
It's gonna cover the cost of that t-bird.
事情的发展是不是很好笑
Isn't that funny how stuff works out?
-的确好笑 -超好笑的
- It sure is funny. - That's hilarious.
我做不到 太冷了
I can't. It's too cold.
要么现在冷五分钟
It's either cold for
要么就变冰冷的尸体
5 minutes or cold forever.
快点
Come on.
说来好笑 我一直以为我会穿着鸟服
Funny -- I always thought I'd be found dead in a bird suit
摔死在大峡谷谷底
at the bottom of the Grand Canyon.
你还是会的 兄弟
You still will, buddy.
你还是会的
You still will.
要是再被我抓到你们喝酒
If I ever catch you drinking again,
你们全校的同学都会看到这张照片
your whole school is going to see this picture.
她骗了我们
Sh-sh-she tricked us.
是啊
I know.
等我们冻死这只虫子 就去找她算账
As soon as we kill this worm, we're gonna get her back.
根本 没有 虫子
There's...no...worm!
没用的 孩子
Not gonna help, kid.
你说得对
You're right.
我不能用酒精麻醉自己的问题
I can't drown my problems in alcohol.
你可以 但那里面是水
Well, you can, but that's water.
你真的打算放弃加州理工吗
You're not really gonna turn down Caltech?
拜托不要跟我说那所大学有多好
Oh, please don't tell me what a great school it is,
我会在两年内毕业
how I'm gonna graduate in two years,
人们会以我的名字命名一个国家什么的
and they're gonna name a country after me.
你有压力
You're feeling some pressure.
万一我是那里最蠢的学生怎么办
What if I'm the dumbest one there?
总得有人是最蠢的
Someone has to be.
我可以去那里 做个蠢学生
I could get there, be dumb,
精神崩溃
have a nervous breakdown --
你会去的 我了解你
You're going. I know you.
你长这么大从没有在挑战面前退缩过
You've never backed down from a challenge your whole life.
现在我可以骗你 告诉你一切会很轻松
Now, I could lie to you and tell you it's gonna be easy.
那样好啊 我现在很脆弱
Well, do that. I'm vulnerable.
我会相信你
I'll believe you.
不会的 会很艰难
It's not. It's gonna be hard.
但你我都知道 这是你必须要做的事
But you and I both know this is something you have to do.
因为如果我不去 我会后悔一辈子
'cause if I don't, I'll regret it my whole life.
是的 是的
I know, I know.
是的 那是一部分原因
Yeah, that's part of it.
我带你去兜个风 有些东西要让你看看
Let's take a ride. Want to show you something.
你不是要带我去贫民区
You're not gonna drive me into a bad neighborhood
让我看看自己有多幸运吧
to show me how lucky I am, are you?
要不是她耍了米奇尔
Well, I would still have my money
我也不会失去我的钱
if she hadn't tricked Mitchell.
你的钱没了真是太糟了啊 小卡
Oh, and it's a shame you don't, Cam.
不然你就可以再买一件那样的大衣了
'cause then you could buy another one of those coats.
我没得到任何我想要的东西
Well, I didn't get anything I wanted!
杰都不喜欢那台世界上最完美的烧烤架
Jay didn't even like the world's most perfect grill.
不是吧
Come on!
这个家庭需要一个领导
The family needs a leader,
而我没法永远做那个领导
and I can't do it forever.
你能胜任的
You can handle it.
我一定要吗
Do I have to?
欲戴王冠 必承其重
Heavy hangs the head.
大学可能并不会那么可怕
You know, college might not be such a big, scary place
要是我能开着...
if I drove up the first --
-别做梦了 -好吧
- Not gonna happen. - Okay.
你弟弟现在财务上有点紧张
Your brother's in a bit of a spot money-wise,
我不想让他难堪
and I don't want to embarrass him,
所以要不就说是我
so how about if I say
送你们两个每人一份礼物
I'm giving you both a gift?
那样他就不会觉得自己是被同情的对象了
That way, he doesn't feel like a charity case.
如果是为了帮米奇尔的话
Well, if it's to help Mitchell...
谢了 乖女儿
Thank you, honey.
还是好冷
S-still s-so cold.
也许喝点咖啡会暖和些
M-maybe some coffee would warm us up.
你上瘾了吧
You have a problem.
听着 要不就说是我
So, listen, how about if I say
送你们两个每人一份礼物
I'm giving you both a gift?
那样你姐姐就...
That way, your sister --
我们收下了
We'll take it.
是的
Yeah.
莉莉 我们可以去买帽子了
Lily, we can get the hats.
好耶
Yeah!